ANDREW ORFALEA

(805) – 570 - 4449 aorfalea@gmail.com Santa Barbara, CA

Motivated and resourceful data scientist with over 10 years of upper management business administration experience. Adaptable, quick learner and always eager for the next challenge. At my core, I'm a people person. Well versed in performing under pressure through collaborative and communicative team dynamics.

SKILLS

- Business Strategy
- Operations Management
- Python
- Git/GitHub
- Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Tableau
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly | Data Science Immersive

January 24, 2022-present

- Full time immersive program which included training in Python, Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning, and Data Visualization.
- Portfolio: https://aothree.github.io/

Freebirds Goleta, CA

General Manager

August 2011 - present

- Analysis of financial statements and adjusting business strategy accordingly. Any recommendations to the owner had to be justified by statistical analysis.
- Accounts Payable. Ensuring 30+ vendors were paid in a timely manner.
- Administered and processed payroll, requiring accuracy of record keeping and timeliness to ensure compliance with all applicable state and federal laws.
- Managing 60+ employees including development, discipline and termination.
- Recruiting and Hiring. Interviewing, onboarding and training.

 Food quality. Responsible for upholding the restaurant's extremely high standards for freshness and flavor. Developed systems to numerically evaluate and record the quality of our ingredients.

Assistant Manager

June 2008 – August 2011

- Projecting hourly sales, for every hour of operation, based on detailed analysis of historical sales data & trends. Based on these projections, scheduling and adjusting labor.
- Scheduling for 60+ coworkers
- Creating and re-formatting forms to analyze data using Microsoft Excel and Google Sheets.
- Maintaining and troubleshooting issues for computers, points of sale and surveillance systems.

EDUCATION

General Assembly
Data Science Immersive

remote January 24 2022 -April 19 2022

Boston College Bachelor of Arts, English Boston, Massachusetts 2008